Dr. Rehana Fatima Shah MBBS | DIUM | MBA (Australia)

Program Management Professional

Apartment No. C-9, 2nd Floor, Crown Towers, Street 91,

Sector G-11/3, Islamabad 44000, Pakistan

Email : fatimarehana@ymail.com

Cell : 0092.307.3731274

0092.331.5143330

Introduction

Technical Skill Set

- ✓ Capacity Building & HRM Support
- √ Case Study Development
- ✓ Coordination & Networking
- ✓ Data Management
- ✓ Disease Surveillance
- ✓ Evaluations
- ✓ Event Management
- ✓ Interpersonal Communication Skills
- ✓ Monitoring
- ✓ M&E Strategies, Systems and Tools
- ✓ On-Site Data Verification Techniques
- ✓ Operational Research
- ✓ Pro-Poor Community based Programming
- ✓ Program Management
- ✓ Public-Private-Partnership Development
- ✓ Quality Assurance Techniques
- ✓ Report Writing
- √ Result based Management
- ✓ Strategic Planning
- ✓ Success Story Documentation
- ✓ Training Manual Development
- √ Training Needs Assessments

I am a medical doctor and a Program Management Professional with over 9 years of professional experience in Primary Health Care & Reproductive Health Programming experience in Emergency Obstetric &



Neonatal Care (EmONC), Family Planning (Healthy Timing & Spacing), Immunization, Vaccine Logistics, Polio and Measles Eradication, Infectious Disease Surveillance, and Tuberculosis (TB) control with the Infinity Development Consultancy Services (Sri Lanka), Technical Resource Facility (TRF), the World Health Organization (WHO), Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA), and the Association of Medical Doctors of Asia (AMDA). Additionally, I have over 6 years of clinical experience in Obstetrics, Gynecology, and Family Medicine in Afghan refugee settlements.

Key achievements of my professional career include Monitoring & Evaluation of research and advocacy projects on MNCH and Reproductive Health; extensive disease surveillance of measles and polio cases in Afghan refugee and peri-urban settlements of Balochistan; Contribution in national research to assess trainings on EmONC and ENC; and Quality Assurance of TB Control activities in conflict affected and border areas.

Linguistic Proficiency					
Language	Proficiency Level	Speaking	Reading	Writing	Areas where language is spoken
English	Excellent	٧	٧	٧	Internationally
Urdu	Excellent	٧	٧	٧	Pakistan, India, Middle East
Persian	Mother Tongue	٧	٧	٧	Pakistan, Iran, Afghanistan, Central Asia
Dari	Excellent	٧	٧	٧	Pakistan, Afghanistan
Pashto	Satisfactory	٧			Pakistan, Afghanistan

EXPERIENCE

Technical Assignments/ Consultancies

Operational Research

- Co-Principal Investigator (Qualitative): Pakistan Nursing Council's National Assessment Study: Management Information Requirements in Pakistan (2012-13)
- MNCH Lead: Design and Development of Pakistan Nursing Council Official Website (2012-13)
- Technical Lead: Development of Automated Online Database for the Pakistan Nursing Council to Record, Register, and Track Nurses, Lady Health Visitors, Community Midwives, and other paramedical staff in Pakistan (2011-12)
- Research Associate: National Research Study commissioned by TRF on assessment of EmONC and ENC trainings in Pakistan (2011)
- MNCH/ Gender Consultant: Mid-term impact evaluation of 'creating good practices in preventing child abuse and strengthening self-reliant resistance against corporal punishment in schools in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa' (2011)
- Co-Principal Investigator (Qualitative): Assessment of the national behavior change communication media campaign for effective malaria control in Pakistan (2010-11)

Clinical Research

Research Officer: Shaukat Khanum Memorial Cancer Hospital & Research Center-Hepatocellular Carcinoma in adult populations in Pakistan (2005)

Capacity Building Trainings Conducted

- Reproductive Health Rights (IDCS)
- Community based Midwifery Services (IDCS)
- Vaccine Logistics Management (JICA)
- Cold Chain Maintenance (JICA)
- EmONC (IDCS)
- Healthy Timing/ Birth Spacing (FALAH)
- Polio Surveillance (WHO)
- Polio Eradication Initiative (WHO)
- Measles Vaccination (UNICEF/WHO)
- Vitamin A administration (WHO)
- Vitamin E administration (WHO)
- Mass Vaccination and Herd Immunity (WHO)

Professional Work Experience

National Medical Officer-EPI & Polio

Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA) National Institute of Child Health (NICH)

January, 2010 to October, 2010 Islamabad

Key Responsibilities: Key responsibilities included providing technical support to the National EPI Program of the Government of Pakistan for Vaccine Logistics Management and Cold Chain Management through capacity building trainings; and conducting analysis of EPI program indicators for the Government supported by the EPI/ Polio Control Project. The project aimed to strengthen routine immunization by providing technical assistance to develop the National Quality Control Laboratory in Islamabad; Support LHW Trainings in routine immunization in partnership with GAVI, the WHO, and other stakeholders.

Achievements: Key achievements included compilation of National EPI statistics for the National EPI Program; Design, Development and Implementation of National Vaccine Logistics Management trainings; Design and Development of National Vaccine Logistics Management training Manual and translation into Urdu; and transliteration of Cold Change Management Training Module for Pakistan.

Program Officer PAIMAN & FALAH

June, 2009 to September, 2009

Islamabad

National Rural Support Program (NRSP)

Key Responsibilities: Key responsibilities included providing technical support, maintain coordination with health authorities and partners of both consortia, capacity building of staff members, implementation, monitoring and supervision of project activities of FALAH and PAIMAN

Achievements: Key achievements included review, development and implementation of Monitoring & Evaluation Plan, M&E Framework in line with the approved project logical frameworks of FALAH and PAIMAN; review and revision of risk mitigation plan of projects; and development of data management protocols of the projects in line with the information requirements of the management consortia.

District Support Officer Polio Eradication Initiative

September, 2005 to October, 2008

Quetta

World Health Organization (WHO)

Key Responsibilities: Key responsibilities included providing technical support, capacity building, and monitoring of Polio and Measles campaigns by the EPI program of the Government of Pakistan; and to conduct disease surveillance of Acute Flaccid Paralysis cases in Quetta and its surrounding region. This was carried out under the Polio Eradication Initiative (PEI) of the World Health Organization, which aimed to eradicate the disease from developing countries around the world through surveillance, monitoring and prevention.

Achievements: Key achievements included prompt and error free compilation of PEI data; successful and efficient disease surveillance in the Quetta region for Acute Flaccid Paralysis (AFP) cases; and conducting capacity building of polio workers, supervisors, and vaccinators from public health facilities in Cold Chain Maintenance.

District TB Supervisor & Data Manager

June, 2005 to September, 2005

Quetta

Association of Medical Doctors of Asia (AMDA)

Key Responsibilities: Key responsibilities included quality assurance, implementation, Supervision, Monitoring & Evaluation of the TB DOTS program for Afghan Refugees in Baluchistan. Conducting health assessments and provision of free medicines for Afghan refugees through the United Nations Repatriation Centre located at Baleli Check-post, Baluchistan. Additionally, provide free treatment; and referral services to refugees from camp sites to the Bolan Medical Complex Health Centre for Leishmaniasis and other diseases. This was done as part of the Directly Observed Treatment Short-course Program for tuberculosis implemented by AMDA in collaboration with the Provincial TB Control Program (PTP) of Balochistan and the American Refugee Committee (ARC).

Achievements: Key achievements included data management of services, supplies and disease prevalence/surveillance data from Refugee Camps; Analysis of collected and compiled data; and development of Procurement, Supply Management Plans for AMDA.

Other Professional Work Experience

Technical Advisor
Maternal & Child Health

February, 2005 to December, 2006

Quetta

The Legends Society

Professional Clinical Experience

Medical Doctor
 Department of Gastroenterology & Hepatology

NHS Fazakerley Hospital, University Hospital Aintree, NHS Trust, Longmoore Lane, Aintree, L9 7AL, Liverpool, England, UK

Consultant-Women's Health & Sonologist

Family Health Consultants

Nasirabad, Alamdar Road, Quetta, Pakistan

Community Service & Philanthropy

- Medical Camps on MNCH for Afghan Refugees in peri-urban settlements of Quetta (Family Health Consultants)
- Establishment of Computer Education Centre for Girls in per-urban Afghan Refugee settlements of Quetta (Personal)
- Ear, Nose and Throat (ENT) Camps for Ultra-poor populations in rural settlements of Tando Allahyar district in Sindh (Pakistan Otolaryngology Society)
- Inter-School Debate Competitions in coastal areas of Karachi (Ziauddin Patient Welfare Society)

EDUCATION

Degrees & Specializations

Medical Doctor (MBBS)

Majors: Surgery, Gynecology-Obstetrics, Medicine & Pediatrics

Master in Business Administration (MBA)

Major: Project Management

Short Courses

- Ultrasonographic Medicine-Whole Body Ultrasound (Professional Diploma Course)
- Medical Transcription (Diploma Course)

CAPACITY BUILDING TRAININGS ATTENDED

- Cold Chain Maintenance (JICA)
- Vaccine Logistics (JICA)
- SMART Chart (ROZAN)
- Family Advancement for Life and Health (Population Council)
- Developing Logical Framework Approach (LFA) for MNCH Programs (JSI)
- Community based Management of Acute Malnutrition-CMAM (UNICEF)
- Normal Labor and EmOC (Greenstar Social Marketing/ PSI)
- Ante-Natal / Post-Natal Care (Greenstar Social Marketing/ PSI)
- Advanced Family Planning (Greenstar Social Marketing/ PSI)
- Neonatal Care (Greenstar Social Marketing/ PSI)
- Child Care (Greenstar Social Marketing/ PSI)
- Emergency Contraception (Greenstar Social Marketing/ PSI)
- Polio Eradication Initiative & the EPI Program (WHO)
- Measles Eradication (UNICEF/ WHO)
- HIV/AIDS Prevention & Control (The Legends Society)
- Care and Support of PLWHAs (The Legends Society)
- Voluntary Counseling & Testing for HIV/AIDS (The Legends Society)
- TB DOTS (AMDA/ ARC)

REFERENCES

Prof. Dr. Ghazna Elmasry Siddiqui, MBBS, MRCOG, FRCOG, Ph.D

Royal Free University Hospital & University College London

Dean of Research & Advocacy, Ziauddin University, Karachi, Pakistan

General Secretary, National Committee-MRCNH, Federal Ministry of National Regulations & Services (Pakistan)

Focal Person (MENA), Royal College of OB-GY, England, UK

International Cell: 0044.781.2142205 | Pakistan Cell: 0092.332.3453376 | email: ghaznas@aol.com

Dr. Syed Muhammad Ali Shah

Public Health & Program Development Professional Advisor, Department of Research & Advocacy, Ziauddin University, Karachi, Pakistan Cell 1: 0092.331.5143330 | Cell 2: 0092.333.7924190 | Email: dralishah@ymail.com

Dr. Syeda Asma Bokhari

Public Health Consultant

International Consultant-Global Fund Grants, Grant Management Solutions-2, USA

Cell: 0092.300.8557495 | Email: bokhari_asma@yahoo.com

Prof. Dr. Rubina Hussain, MBBS, MRCOG, FRCOG

Health of the Department-OBGY, Ziauddin University, Karachi, Pakistan Country Committee (Pakistan) of Royal College of OB-GY, England, UK Pakistan Cell: 0092.333.2121945 | email: drrubinahussain@gmail.com

Dr. Raul Rico Bonifacio

Former Team Leader-Polio Eradication Initiative, World Health Organization Technical expert, EMRO, World Health Organization Email: rrbonifacio@hotmail.com